<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Harbour</title>
    <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James Harbour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://kyrem1.github.io/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anime</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/anime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/anime/</guid>
      <description>MyAnimeList About 3x3s in the Anime Community &amp;ldquo;3x3s&amp;rdquo; in the anime community refer to a grid of nine images arranged in a three-by-three format, each representing an anime that the person has chosen as their favorites or as representative of their taste. This format allows anime fans to quickly and visually share their preferences with others, sparking discussions and helping to find common ground or explore new titles.
Creating a 3x3 is often seen as a personal and introspective activity, as it requires the individual to reflect on which anime have had the most significant impact on them or resonate with their preferences.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h3 id="myanimelisthttpsmyanimelistnetprofileiamtacky"><a href="https://myanimelist.net/profile/iamtacky">MyAnimeList</a></h3>
<h3 id="about-3x3s-in-the-anime-community">About 3x3s in the Anime Community</h3>
<p>&ldquo;3x3s&rdquo; in the anime community refer to a grid of nine images arranged in a three-by-three format, each representing an anime that the person has chosen as their favorites or as representative of their taste. This format allows anime fans to quickly and visually share their preferences with others, sparking discussions and helping to find common ground or explore new titles.</p>
<p>Creating a 3x3 is often seen as a personal and introspective activity, as it requires the individual to reflect on which anime have had the most significant impact on them or resonate with their preferences. The choices can vary widely, from mainstream hits to obscure gems, showcasing the diversity within the anime community.</p>
<p>Moreover, 3x3s can evolve over time, reflecting the changing tastes and experiences of the individual. They are often shared on social media platforms, anime forums, and community groups, leading to exchanges of opinions, recommendations, and sometimes debates about the merits of certain anime.</p>
<p>In essence, the 3x3 serves as a snapshot of a person&rsquo;s anime journey, encapsulating their past experiences, current favorites, and future interests in a compact, visually appealing format.</p>
<h3 id="2024-present">2024-Present</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="">Yuru Camp</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2020-2023-3x3">2020-2023 3x3</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="3x3anime.jpg" alt="img"  />
</p>
<p>Here are my above 3x3 entries listed from left to right and top to bottom:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/239/Gankutsuou">Gankutsuou</a>
<ul>
<li>An anime adaptation of the classic novel <em>The Count of Monte Cristo</em>, set in 5053 space-France. It takes the best revenge story ever written into the world of anime. Has a wonderful slow build just like the novel, where the Count sets up dominoes in front of your eyes but you just don&rsquo;t know it yet. Once the dominoes start to fall, this show becomes purely epic.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/7724/Shiki">Shiki</a>
<ul>
<li>Since I went in <em>completely blind</em>, my experience with this one during the first half of the show is likely different than others; however, I actually think that this is the ideal state-of-mind to begin this show with. As such, spoiler tags ahead. Basically, it took me like 4-5 episodes to realize this show was about vampires. This show is terrifying not in its literal horrific aspects, but in its portrayal of the lengths by which humans will go to preserve their own existence. Truly harrowing, this anime left me empty.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/13759/Sakura-sou_no_Pet_na_Kanojo">Sakura-sou no Pet na Kanojo</a>
<ul>
<li>A cute romcom that explores the ideas of mediocrity in the face of overwhelming genius. It provides a path to contentedness following ones realization that, no matter what you are doing, there will always be someone better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/820/Ginga_Eiyuu_Densetsu">Legend of the Galactic Heroes</a>
<ul>
<li>Imagine Star Wars but with strategic warfare backed by famous concertos/operas instead of lightsaber fights. One of the first space operas. It explores the age old question of whether one should prefer a poor democracy or an impeccable autocracy. The nuance in this show comes from the fact that it never seeks to answer this question, but merely provides viewers with the necessary prompting to come to their own conclusions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/17265/Log_Horizon">Log Horizon</a>
<ul>
<li>What type of political system would arise in a fantasy world running on game logic where the population is comprised of MMO gamers? Log Horizon explores this question in a thorougly intelligent manner. The best isekai by far. This show is largely dialogue-driven, so if you are looking for mainly action-based progression then this show is not for you. See Digibro&rsquo;s youtube analysis series of this show for further details on why it&rsquo;s genius.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/467/Koukaku_Kidoutai__Stand_Alone_Complex">Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex</a>
<ul>
<li>The original <em>Ghost in the Shell</em> film was the progenitor for sci-fi anime and set the tone for the genre. It utilized the setting to address incredibly poigniant themes such as the nature of intelligence and the soul. The spin-off series <em>Stand Alone Complex</em> further pursues these themes with the precision of a scalpel. The show has thematic fish to fry and it isn&rsquo;t afraid to go all in.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/339/Serial_Experiments_Lain">Serial Experiments Lain</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/9253/Steins_Gate">Steins Gate</a>
<ul>
<li>It&rsquo;s hard to write about things which embed themselves within your core memory, as you can&rsquo;t imagine what it was like before you experienced said thing. Steins Gate is one of those shows.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/4181/Clannad__After_Story">Clannad: After Story</a>
<ul>
<li>Even though I skipped the original Clannad, this series still made me ball for days on end. I don&rsquo;t think anything has ever hit me as hard as this show has. Truly an emotional masterpiece.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="otaku-related-interests">Otaku-related Interests</h3>
<ul>
<li>Denpa</li>
<li>Gunpla</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/music/</guid>
      <description>3x3 Collection 2023 2021 Entries (left to right top to bottom) 2023: Sunbather, Deafheaven In Rainbows, Radiohead LSD and the Search for God Selected Ambient Works 85-92, Aphex Twin &amp;lsquo;77 Live, Les Rallizes Dénudés Jane Doe, Converge White Pony, Deftones Dopethrone, Electric Wizard Take Me to Your Leader, King Geedorah 2021: Portal of I, Ne Obliviscaris Chet Baker Sings For You, Tatsuro Yamashita All of Me, Masayoshi Takanaka N.O.I.S.E., Ghostemane Exercises in Futility, mgla World is Yours, Mass of the Fermenting Dregs Dopethrone, Electric Wizard MadVillany, MF Doom </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="3x3-collection">3x3 Collection</h1>

<style>
.container {
  display: flex;
  flex-direction: row;
  flex-wrap: nowrap;
  align-items: flex-start;
  justify-content: center;
  width: 100%;
  margin: 0 auto;
}

.figure {
  margin-right: 20px; /* Increased spacing between images */
  text-align: center; /* Center-align the caption */
}

.figure img {
  width: 300px; /* Or your desired width */
  height: 300px; /* Or your desired height */
  padding: 2px; /* Adjust padding as needed */
  box-shadow: 0 0px; /* Adjust or remove shadow as needed */
}

.figure figcaption {
  color: rgba(30, 30, 30, 0.8); /* Adjust caption text color as needed */
}

/* Remove margin from the last figure to avoid unnecessary spacing on the right */
.container .figure:last-child {
  margin-right: 0;
}
</style>

<div class="container" style="width: 800px; max-width: 100%;">
 <figure class="figure">
    <img src="3x3music2023_1200.jpg" alt="2023">
    <figcaption>2023</figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure class="figure">
    <img src="3x3music2021_1200.jpg" alt="2021">
    <figcaption>2021</figcaption>
  </figure>
  
</div>


<h2 id="entries-left-to-right-top-to-bottom">Entries (left to right top to bottom)</h2>
<h3 id="2023">2023:</h3>
<ul>
<li><em>Sunbather</em>, Deafheaven</li>
<li><em>In Rainbows</em>, Radiohead</li>
<li><em>LSD and the Search for God</em></li>
<li><em>Selected Ambient Works 85-92</em>, Aphex Twin</li>
<li><em>&lsquo;77 Live</em>, Les Rallizes Dénudés</li>
<li><em>Jane Doe</em>, Converge</li>
<li><em>White Pony</em>, Deftones</li>
<li><em>Dopethrone</em>, Electric Wizard</li>
<li><em>Take Me to Your Leader</em>, King Geedorah</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2021">2021:</h3>
<ul>
<li><em>Portal of I</em>, Ne Obliviscaris</li>
<li><em>Chet Baker Sings</em></li>
<li><em>For You</em>, Tatsuro Yamashita</li>
<li><em>All of Me</em>, Masayoshi Takanaka</li>
<li><em>N.O.I.S.E.</em>, Ghostemane</li>
<li><em>Exercises in Futility</em>, mgla</li>
<li><em>World is Yours</em>, Mass of the Fermenting Dregs</li>
<li><em>Dopethrone</em>, Electric Wizard</li>
<li><em>MadVillany</em>, MF Doom</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
