<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>James Harbour</title>
    <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James Harbour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kyrem1.github.io/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anime</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/anime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/anime/</guid>
      <description>MyAnimeList My current 3x3 Here are my above 3x3 entries listed from left to right and top to bottom:
Gankutsuou An anime adaptation of the classic novel The Count of Monte Cristo, set in 5053 space-France. It takes the best revenge story ever written into the world of anime. Has a wonderful slow build just like the novel, where the Count sets up dominoes in front of your eyes but you just don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="myanimelisthttpsmyanimelistnetprofilekyrem1"><a href="https://myanimelist.net/profile/kyrem1">MyAnimeList</a></h3>
<h3 id="my-current-3x3">My current 3x3</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="3x3anime.jpg" alt="img"  />
</p>
<p>Here are my above 3x3 entries listed from left to right and top to bottom:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/239/Gankutsuou">Gankutsuou</a>
<ul>
<li>An anime adaptation of the classic novel <em>The Count of Monte Cristo</em>, set in 5053 space-France. It takes the best revenge story ever written into the world of anime. Has a wonderful slow build just like the novel, where the Count sets up dominoes in front of your eyes but you just don&rsquo;t know it yet. Once the dominoes start to fall, this show becomes purely epic.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/7724/Shiki">Shiki</a>
<ul>
<li>Since I went in <em>completely blind</em>, my experience with this one during the first half of the show is likely different than others; however, I actually think that this is the ideal state-of-mind to begin this show with. As such, spoiler tags ahead. Basically, it took me like 4-5 episodes to realize this show was about vampires. This show is terrifying not in its literal horrific aspects, but in its portrayal of the lengths by which humans will go to preserve their own existence. Truly harrowing, this anime left me empty.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/13759/Sakura-sou_no_Pet_na_Kanojo">Sakura-sou no Pet na Kanojo</a>
<ul>
<li>A cute romcom that explores the ideas of mediocrity in the face of overwhelming genius. It provides a path to contentedness following ones realization that, no matter what you are doing, there will always be someone better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/820/Ginga_Eiyuu_Densetsu">Legend of the Galactic Heroes</a>
<ul>
<li>Imagine Star Wars but with strategic warfare backed by famous concertos/operas instead of lightsaber fights. One of the first space operas. It explores the age old question of whether one should prefer a poor democracy or an impeccable autocracy. The nuance in this show comes from the fact that it never seeks to answer this question, but merely provides viewers with the necessary prompting to come to their own conclusions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/17265/Log_Horizon">Log Horizon</a>
<ul>
<li>What type of political system would arise in a fantasy world running on game logic where the population is comprised of MMO gamers? Log Horizon explores this question in a thorougly intelligent manner. The best isekai by far. This show is largely dialogue-driven, so if you are looking for mainly action-based progression then this show is not for you. See Digibro&rsquo;s youtube analysis series of this show for further details on why it&rsquo;s genius.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/467/Koukaku_Kidoutai__Stand_Alone_Complex">Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex</a>
<ul>
<li>The original <em>Ghost in the Shell</em> film was the progenitor for sci-fi anime and set the tone for the genre. It utilized the setting to address incredibly poigniant themes such as the nature of intelligence and the soul. The spin-off series <em>Stand Alone Complex</em> further pursues these themes with the precision of a scalpel. The show has thematic fish to fry and it isn&rsquo;t afraid to go all in.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/339/Serial_Experiments_Lain">Serial Experiments Lain</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/9253/Steins_Gate">Steins Gate</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/4181/Clannad__After_Story">Clannad: After Story</a>
<ul>
<li>Even though I skipped the original Clannad, this series still made me ball for days on end. I don&rsquo;t think anything has ever hit me as hard as this show has. Truly an emotional masterpiece.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="my-otaku-interests">My Otaku Interests</h3>
<ul>
<li>Denpa</li>
<li>Gunpla</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/music/</guid>
      <description>My Current 3x3 Here are my above 3x3 entries listed from left to right and top to bottom:
Portal of I, Ne Obliviscaris TODO Chet Baker Sings TODO For You, Tatsuro Yamashita TODO All of Me, Masayoshi Takanaka TODO N.O.I.S.E., Ghostemane TODO Exercises in Futility, mgla TODO World is Yours, Mass of the Fermenting Dregs From the first few seconds, this album exudes a sense of freedom that is hard to find in the modern music landscape.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="my-current-3x3">My Current 3x3</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="3x3music1200.jpg" alt="3x3 music"  />
</p>
<p>Here are my above 3x3 entries listed from left to right and top to bottom:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href=""><em>Portal of I</em>, Ne Obliviscaris</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>Chet Baker Sings</em></a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>For You</em>, Tatsuro Yamashita</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>All of Me</em>, Masayoshi Takanaka</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>N.O.I.S.E.</em>, Ghostemane</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>Exercises in Futility</em>, mgla</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>World is Yours</em>, Mass of the Fermenting Dregs</a>
<ul>
<li>From the first few seconds, this album exudes a sense of freedom that is hard to find in the modern music landscape. I would say that this work is closest to the excellent FLCL soundtrack by The Pillows. This is music that makes you feel like a kid again.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>Dopethrone</em>, Electric Wizard</a>
<ul>
<li>This album is for those who take their coffee black and bitter. It will make you <em>feel</em> that the world is on an inevitable death march towards a cruel future with no chance of return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href=""><em>MadVillany</em>, MF Doom</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="genres">Genres</h2>
<p>I listen to a wide variety of genres including, but not limited to, the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Metal
<ul>
<li>Black Metal</li>
<li>Death Metal</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Jazz
<ul>
<li>50s-60s Jazz</li>
<li>Bebop</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Hip-Hop/Rap
<ul>
<li>Underground</li>
<li>Phonk</li>
<li>Screamo</li>
<li>Boombap</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Classical</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
