<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>James Harbour</title>
    <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James Harbour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kyrem1.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Black Metal?</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/blog/blackmetal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/blog/blackmetal/</guid>
      <description>I never play my favorite genre on the aux. I&amp;rsquo;m perfectly fine with that; I like enough genres that it is never hard to find something that will suit any present company.
A couple times, I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked about why I enjoy the &amp;ldquo;noise&amp;rdquo; that I listen to so much, but my answers have always gotten interrupted. This is the uninteruppted version.
I can&amp;rsquo;t quite remember when exactly I discovered black metal.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I never play my favorite genre on the aux. I&rsquo;m perfectly fine with that; I like enough genres that it is never hard to find something that will suit any present company.</p>
<p>A couple times, I&rsquo;ve been asked about why I enjoy the &ldquo;noise&rdquo; that I listen to so much, but my answers have always gotten interrupted. This is the uninteruppted version.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t quite remember when exactly I discovered black metal. I had been in the metal scene for a while listening to prog metal from bands such as Ne Obliviscaris and Xanathochroid, and I gradually shifted towards the heavier side of metal in Death Metal. I was and still am a major Spawn of Possession and Angelmaker fan. However, one thing that this heavier side of metal lacked in my eyes was emotional depth. Behind the blistering blastbeats and gut-curdling screams, it is hard to find any emotional backbone besides the expression of pure, unadulterated rage.</p>
<p>Thankfully, rage is an emotion that does not quite resonate with me; however, this meant that I had little emotional resonance with the music I was listening to. And then, I discovered black metal.</p>
<p>Black metal is an attempt to add such an emotional backbone to death metal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The appeal of Vtubers</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/blog/vtubers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/blog/vtubers/</guid>
      <description>Around the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, I entered into</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Around the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, I entered into</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anime</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/hobbies/anime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/hobbies/anime/</guid>
      <description>MyAnimeList My current 3x3 Here are my above 3x3 entries listed from left to right and top to bottom:
Gankutsuou An anime adaptation of the classic novel The Count of Monte Cristo, set in 5053 space-France. It takes the best revenge story ever written into the world of anime. Has a wonderful slow build just like the novel, where the Count sets up dominoes in front of your eyes but you just don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="myanimelisthttpsmyanimelistnetprofilekyrem1"><a href="https://myanimelist.net/profile/kyrem1">MyAnimeList</a></h3>
<h3 id="my-current-3x3">My current 3x3</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="3x3anime.jpg" alt="img"  />
</p>
<p>Here are my above 3x3 entries listed from left to right and top to bottom:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/239/Gankutsuou">Gankutsuou</a>
<ul>
<li>An anime adaptation of the classic novel <em>The Count of Monte Cristo</em>, set in 5053 space-France. It takes the best revenge story ever written into the world of anime. Has a wonderful slow build just like the novel, where the Count sets up dominoes in front of your eyes but you just don&rsquo;t know it yet. Once the dominoes start to fall, this show becomes purely epic.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/7724/Shiki">Shiki</a>
<ul>
<li>Since I went in <em>completely blind</em>, my experience with this one during the first half of the show is likely different than others; however, I actually think that this is the ideal state-of-mind to begin this show with. As such, spoiler tags ahead. Basically, it took me like 4-5 episodes to realize this show was about vampires. This show is terrifying not in its literal horrific aspects, but in its portrayal of the lengths by which humans will go to preserve their own existence. Truly harrowing, this anime left me empty.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/13759/Sakura-sou_no_Pet_na_Kanojo">Sakura-sou no Pet na Kanojo</a>
<ul>
<li>A cute romcom that explores the ideas of mediocrity in the face of overwhelming genius. It provides a path to contentedness following ones realization that, no matter what you are doing, there will always be someone better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/820/Ginga_Eiyuu_Densetsu">Legend of the Galactic Heroes</a>
<ul>
<li>Imagine Star Wars but with strategic warfare backed by famous concertos/operas instead of lightsaber fights. One of the first space operas. It explores the age old question of whether one should prefer a poor democracy or an impeccable autocracy. The nuance in this show comes from the fact that it never seeks to answer this question, but merely provides viewers with the necessary prompting to come to their own conclusions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/17265/Log_Horizon">Log Horizon</a>
<ul>
<li>What type of political system would arise in a fantasy world running on game logic where the population is comprised of MMO gamers? Log Horizon explores this question in a thorougly intelligent manner. The best isekai by far. This show is largely dialogue-driven, so if you are looking for mainly action-based progression then this show is not for you. See Digibro&rsquo;s youtube analysis series of this show for further details on why it&rsquo;s genius.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/467/Koukaku_Kidoutai__Stand_Alone_Complex">Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/339/Serial_Experiments_Lain">Serial Experiments Lain</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/9253/Steins_Gate">Steins Gate</a>
<ul>
<li>TODO</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/4181/Clannad__After_Story">Clannad: After Story</a>
<ul>
<li>Even though I skipped the original Clannad, this series still made me ball for days on end. I don&rsquo;t think anything has ever hit me as hard as this show has. Truly an emotional masterpiece.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="my-otaku-interests">My Otaku Interests</h3>
<ul>
<li>Denpa</li>
<li>Gunpla</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/hobbies/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kyrem1.github.io/other/hobbies/music/</guid>
      <description> ⠀ ⠀ I listen to a wide variety of genres including, but not limited to, the following:
Metal Black Metal Death Metal Jazz 50s-60s Jazz Bebop Hip-Hop/Rap Underground Phonk Screamo Boombap Classical </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="3x3music1200.jpg" alt="3x3 music"  />
</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center">⠀</th>
<th style="text-align:center">⠀</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center"><img loading="lazy" src="3x3music600.jpg" alt="3x3 music"  />
</td>
<td style="text-align:center"><img loading="lazy" src="3x3music600.jpg" alt="3x3 music"  />
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I listen to a wide variety of genres including, but not limited to, the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Metal
<ul>
<li>Black Metal</li>
<li>Death Metal</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Jazz
<ul>
<li>50s-60s Jazz</li>
<li>Bebop</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Hip-Hop/Rap
<ul>
<li>Underground</li>
<li>Phonk</li>
<li>Screamo</li>
<li>Boombap</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Classical</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
